# Kieran Lynch

## Chicago, IL

Lynch.kieran1@gmail.com | (309) 256-5240 https://www.linkedin.com/in/kieran-lynch-516525145

### **SUMMARY**

Customer Success professional with over three years of product adoption and project management success. Experienced in data analysis, relationship management, and increasing product adoption within the travel technology industry. Skilled in training internal and external stakeholders on product strategy, enhancements, and best practices.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## RoomIt by CWT, Chicago, IL

June 2017-Present

Business Development Manager (Oct 2019 – Present)

- Responsible for ensuring customer success and driving adoption of our API content delivery strategy
- Serve as the SME for our Energy, Resource, and Marine portfolio of global customers, and leading client travel technology strategy for clients up to \$500M in travel spend (accounts included BP, Chevron, & Shell)
- Create and lead an ongoing education program for account managers within the ERM division specifically how to position our technology, utilize our data, and create benefit projection models

Business Development Associate (Feb 2018 – Sept 2019)

- Responsible for increasing adoption and utilization of our booking software (delivered via API) throughout a portfolio of customers in North America, supporting clients up to \$120M in spend (accounts included Citrix, Insight, & ServiceNow)
- Lead monthly education sessions/webinars for audiences of up to 250 individuals
- Responsible for rollout, training, and delivery of 8-10 new product implementations concurrently

SMB Account Representative (June 2017 – Feb 2018)

- Drive transactions and incremental revenue throughout organizations with up to \$5M in travel spend
- Utilize Oracle Sales Cloud to organize and manage all accounts and opportunities
- Analyze buyer behavior within the SMB space and serve as 'voice of customer' to better develop our technology and offering

# Beijing Foton Cummins Engine Company, Beijing, China

May 2015-Aug 2015

Logistics Intern

- Analyzed shipping routes and inventory levels to align with forecasts
- Reconciled prices and aftermarket service with customers and other departments
- Compared actual vs. forecasted sales for specific regions throughout APAC
- Worked in a team of 5 people to transition and set-up a new VMI warehouse
- Translated business documents from English to Chinese, and Chinese to English

### **SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE**

- Oracle Sales Cloud
- ServiceNow
- Tableau
- Oracle Business Intelligence Tools
- Microsoft Office

- API Interaction (API, JSON, AJAX)
- Agile framework
- MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node)
- Browser based tech (HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Storage)
- Python & Django

#### **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

Certificate, Full Stack Development

Illinois State University, Normal, IL

May 2017

Bachelor of Science - International Business, Bachelor of Science - Finance

October 2020